Guide to the National Lesbian and Gay Law Association (U.S.) records,1988-2015.
National Lesbian and Gay Law Association (U.S.) records,1988-20158.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
National Lesbian and Gay Law Association (U.S.) records, 1988-2015.
7742
National Lesbian and Gay Law Association (U.S.)
6.4 cubic feet
Administrative files, conference materials and ephemera, law publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Programs and planning documents for Lavender Law conferences, Board of Directors files, by-laws and long-range planning documents, correspondence, and brochures, t-shirts, and other publicity pieces for the National Lesbian and Gay Law Association.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The National Lesbian and Gay Law Association (NLGLA) is a national association of lawyers, judges and other legal professionals, law students, activists, and affiliated lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender legal organizations. NLGLA promotes justice in and through the legal profession for the LGBT community in all its diversity.
At the 1987 march on Washington, DC for lesbian and gay rights, the idea of creating a national lesbian and gay bar association was introduced. The first Lavender Law® conference was held in San Francisco, in November 1988. In 1989, at the American Bar Association Mid-Year meeting, by-laws were presented, and a nonprofit board of directors was formalized. By the time of the second board meeting in 1989 in Boston, the National Lesbian and Gay Law Association (NLGLA) had 293 paid members. NLGLA initiated a campaign to ask the American Bar Assocation (ABA) to include protection based upon on sexual orientation to its revision of the Model Code of Judicial Conduct for Judges, which has now been accepted by several states. In 1992, NLGLA became an official affiliate of the American Bar Association and it now works closely with the ABA's Section on Individual Rights and Responsibilities and its Committee on Sexual Orientation and Gender Identity.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Programs and planning documents for Lavender Law conferences, Board of Directors files, by-laws and long-range planning documents, correspondence, and brochures, t-shirts, and other publicity pieces for the National Lesbian and Gay Law Association.
SUBJECTS
Names:
National Lesbian and Gay Law Association (U.S.)
Subjects:
Homosexuality--Law and legislation.; Gays--Legal status, laws, etc.; Lesbians--Legal status, laws, etc.; Bias (Law).; Civil rights--Law and legislation.; Unmarried couples--Legal status, laws, etc.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Collecting program: Human Sexuality Collection.
SERIES LIST
Series I. National Organization
Boxes 1-2, 10
Series II. Conferences
Boxes 2-9
Series III. Affiliate Organizations
Box 6
Series IV. Educational and Informative Publications Related to Lesbian/Gay Law
Box 6, 9
Series V. Audio-Visual Material
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. National Organization
  - Bylaws, Structure, and Long-Term Planning
    - Bylaws, October 18, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bylaws, August 1, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Business Plan, August 1997 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Natalie Butto Restructure/Long Term Plan, July 1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Natalie Butto Restructure/Long Term Plan, January 1997 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
    - James Schwartz Bylaw Committee, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors Policies and Procedures, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Membership Marketing Plan, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Policies and Procedures, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Bylaws, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bylaws, Amendments, and Organizational Proposals, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Long Range Planning, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - "Grants for Minorities", 1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - How to Form a Lesbian/Gay Law Association, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Bylaws and Articles of Incorporation of NLGLA Organizations (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Policies and Procedures (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Board of Directors
    - Board of Directors Meeting--Agenda and Meeting Documents, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Agendas, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Minutes, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Messages Regarding Membership, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Board Member Reports, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Board Meetings, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
    - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - History, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Agendas, Miscellaneous, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Judicial Education and Selection Committee Board Member Report, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Board of Directors, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 32-33)
    - NLGLA Meeting Photographs, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Board Meetings, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Board of Directors, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Legal Counsil, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Committees, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Balance Sheets (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Judicial Nominations Projects (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Membership (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Minutes, 1998-2004 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence and board lists, 2003-2005 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Corporate Application for Exemption, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - March on Washington, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Profit and Loss Budget, membership directory, 1999-2005 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Corporate papers, 1991-1994 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, Bylaws, and Lists of Board Members, 1997-2000 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Bar Association Correspondence, 1990-1996 (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
    - Minutes, 1991-1998 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Board lists, outdated bylaws, and miscellaneous correspondence, 2000-2003 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Amicus Curiae Briefs
    - NLGLA Amicus Curiae Brief Policy (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Forum for Academic and Institutional Rights v. Rumsfeld (Box 1, Folder 45-47)
    - Amicus Curiae Briefs, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Amicus Curiae Briefs (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters and Brochures
    - Brochures (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Law and Sexuality: The Official Legal Journal of the NLGLA (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence Regarding Newsletters, 1993-1997 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Newsletters, 1995-2004 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Newsletters, 1990-1994 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Membership Directory, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Membership Directory, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
    - Membership Directory, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Membership Directory Correspondence, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Membership Directory, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Membership Directory, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Internal Files
- Series II. Conferences
  - Lavender Law I (1988 San Francisco)
    - "Timeline" (Program Committee) (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Speakers (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Publicity and Attendance (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Sourcebook, with some correspondence (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Lavender Law II, 1990 Atlanta
    - Program Committee (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Speaker Suggestions (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Minority Speaker Suggestions (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Potential Speakers and Panels (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
    - Speakers (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Topic Areas (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Sodomy Law Reform Day (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - AIDS Law Day (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Publicity (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Program and Schedule (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Post-Conference Reports (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Evaluations (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Mailer and pamphlet (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Lavender Law II, 1991
    - Program (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Lavender Law III, 1992 Chicago
    - Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Biographies and Resumes (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - "Activist Tract"--Civil Rights Speakers (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Conference materials (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Attendees' Welcome Materials (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - AIDS Law Day (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Copies of Program pamphlet (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Lavender Law, 1993 Seattle
    - Schedule and program (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Lavender Law IV, 1994 Portland
    - Executive Committee (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Location Selection Process (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Panelist Biographies (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Panelist Questionnaire (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Continuing Legal Education (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Tentative Agendas (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Publicity (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Materials for First Day (AIDS/Family/Anti-Gay Initiatives Law Day) (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Materials for General Conference Programming (Bound and Loose Copies) (Box 3, Folder 9-11)
    - Program (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Lavender Law V 1996, New Orleans
    - Location Selection Process (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence and Event Planning (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Continuing Legal Education (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Publicity and Mass Mailings (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Conference Materials (Binder 1) (Box 3, Folder 16-18)
    - Conference Materials (Binder 2) (Box 3, Folder 19-21)
    - Conference Materials (Binder 3--Official Copy) (Box 3, Folder 22-24)
    - White and Black Lavender Law V T-Shirts (Box 7)
    - Program (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Lavender Law 1997, West Hollywood
    - On-Site Inspection Report (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence and Event Planning (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Endorsements and Program Advertising (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Gill Foundation Grant (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Publicity and Mass Mailings (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Drafts of Welcome Materials (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Conference Materials (Box 4, Folder 7-10)
    - Post-Conference Feedback (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Program and booklet (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Lavender Law 1998, Boston
    - Correspondence and Event Planning (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Publicity and Mass Mailings (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Program and letter (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Lavender Law 1999, Seattle
    - Location Search: Madison Renaissance Hotel (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Publicity and Mass Mailings (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Conference Materials (Box 4, Folder 16-18)
    - Melinda M. Whiteway Nametag (Box 7)
    - Program and schedule (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Lavender Law 2000, Washington D.C.
    - Brochures and Website (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Conference Materials (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Programs, two volumes of conference session material (Box 9, Folder 11-12)
  - Lavender Law 2001, Dallas
    - Conference Materials (Box 4, Folder 21-24)
    - Employment Law Panel (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Session booklets (Box 9, Folder 13-14)
  - Lavender Law 2002, Philadelphia
    - Publicity and Mass Mailings (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Conference Materials: Programs (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Conference Materials (Box 5, Folder 1-5)
    - Program, Panels and Bios (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Lavender Law 2003, New York City
    - Conference Materials: Programs, Brochures, and CD-ROMs (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Conference Materials (Binder 1) (Box 5, Folder 7-11)
    - Conference Materials (Binder 2) (Box 5, Folder 12-16)
    - White Lavender Law 2003 T-Shirt (Box 7)
  - Lavender Law 2004, Minneapolis
    - Conference Materials: Programs, Brochures, and CD-ROMs (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Conference Materials (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Conference Materials, Continued (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - D'Arcy Kemnitz Nametags (Box 7)
    - Career Fair (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Lavender Law 2005, San Diego
    - Conference Materials: Programs and Brochures (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Programs, Career Fair, and magnets (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Lavender Law 2006, Washington D.C.
    - Publicity and Mass Mailings (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Programs and CD-ROMs (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Lavender Law 2007, Chicago
    - Publicity and CD-ROM (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Publicity, mailers, and magnets (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Lavender Law 2008, San Francisco
    - Publicity, Program, and CD-ROM (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Lavender Law 2009, New York
    - Program (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Lavender Law 2010, Miami
    - Program (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Lavender Law 2011, Hollywood
    - Program (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Lavender Law 2012, Washington D.C.
    - Program (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Lavender Law conference programs and brochures, 2008-2015 (Box 8)
  - Regional Conferences
    - "How to Do a Regional Conference" Packet (by Margaret Fine), 1993 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Brochures, 1991-1995 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Regional Conferences, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Regional Conferences, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Out and Proud Corporate Counsel Institute and Award Reception, 2013 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - GLBT Legal Symposium and CLE Day, 2011 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Series III. Affiliate Organizations
  - Lists of Organizations (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Events, 1993-2005 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - American Bar Association: Continuing Legal Education Material, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - American Bar Association: Allies for Justice Award (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - American Bar Association: "Answering the Call" Service Project, 2005-2006 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - American Bar Association: HIV/AIDS Law and Practice, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
  - American Bar Association (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Bay Area Lawyers for Individual Freedom (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - International Gay and Lesbian Association (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Gay and Lesbian Attorneys of Washington (GAYLAW) (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Gay/Lesbian Legal Referral Service (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Lawyers for Human Rights (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Massachusetts Lesbian and Gay Bar Association (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - National Center for Lesbian Rights (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - National Youth Advocacy Coalition (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Series IV. Educational and Informative Publications Related to Lesbian/Gay Law
  - Law Journals A-G (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Law Journals L-Y (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - News Publications, 1990-1999 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Educational Materials (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Report of the DC Bar Task Force on sexual orientation and the legal workplace, 1999-2000 (Box 8)
  - Los Angeles Bar Studies, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - San Francisco Bar Studies, 1991, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - New York Bar Studies, 2005 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Bar Oath Association (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Biases, 1996, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Solomon Amendment, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Domestic Violence materials (Box 9, Folder 30)
- Series V. Audio-Visual Material
  - Lavender Law Conference cassettes, 1988; tr-10854-10879 (Box 11)
  - Ambassador Ballroom, September 9, 2006; V-9074-9076 (Box 11)
  - Diplomat Ballroom, Dan Bradley luncheon, September 9, 2006; V-9077 (Box 11)
  - Dan Bradley award ceremony, August 26, 2010; V-9078 (Box 11)
  - Regency, September 8, 2006; V-9079-9080 (Box 11)
  - Lavender Law: Same Sex Relationships, September 8, 2007; V-9081 (Box 11)
  - Ethics in Immigration, 2007; V-9082 (Box 11)
  - Leveraging your professional advantage through diversity, 2007; V-9083 (Box 11)
  - Lavender Law, 2007; V-9084 (Box 11)
  - Lavender Law: Dismantling Gender, 2007; V-9085 (Box 11)
  - Estate Planning for Same Sex Couples, 2007; V-9086 (Box 11)
  - Lavender Law: Examining 'Backlash', 2007; V-9087 (Box 11)
  - LGBT ProBono in Private Practice, 2007; V-9088 (Box 11)
  - Lavender Law: Speech in the Culture Wars, 2007; V-9089 (Box 11)